<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <atom:link href="http://www.galindolaw.com/feed-all.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
     <title>Law offices of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C. Feed</title>
     <link>http://www.galindolaw.com/</link>
     <description>Law offices of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C. Feed</description>
     <language>en-us</language>
     <copyright>2015 Law offices of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C., All Rights Reserved, Reproduced with Permission</copyright>
     <docs>http://www.galindolaw.com/</docs>
     <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 11:08:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
     <image>
        <title>Law offices of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C. Feed</title>
        <url>http://www.galindolaw.com/images/logoprint.gif</url>
        <link>http://www.galindolaw.com/</link>
     </image>
    
<item><title><![CDATA[Injury Caused by Teen or Unlicensed Drivers]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Under Texas law, if you give permission to a driver who you know is unlicensed, incompetent or reckless to operate your vehicle; you may be held liable for their negligent acts. This is known as negligent entrustment.</p><p>Likewise, if you are injured by an unlicensed, incompetent or reckless driver, it does not mean that you or your insurance company will be stuck paying your medical bills and costs to repair your vehicle. You may seek compensation for your injuries from the owner of the other vehicle as well as the driver who caused the accident.</p><p>In a negligent entrustment suit, the driver who causes the <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/practice_areas/get-justice-after-a-houston-car-accident.cfm">accident</a> is sometimes excluded or not covered by the automobile insurance policy which the owner of the vehicle carries. This happens frequently when an unlicensed teenager is entrusted with the use of their parent&rsquo;s vehicle and causes an accident. An owner of a car may also be liable if the owner lent his or her car to someone they knew had a history of car accidents.</p><p>&nbsp;If you are involved in an accident in which the other driver is someone other than the owner, there are sources of monetary compensation available under Texas law.</p><p>Contact the law office of Cristobal Galindo, P.C. for <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/bio.cfm">experienced lawyers</a> to represent you if you are injured in such an accident.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/injury-caused-by-teen-or-unlicensed-drivers.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-137346</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 12:34:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How much does it cost to get a personal injury attorney?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Most cases are taken on a contingency fee basis. This means the <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/practice_areas/get-justice-after-a-houston-car-accident.cfm">injured victim</a> or the victim&rsquo;s family members are not responsible for any attorney&rsquo;s fees or court costs until after a settlement is reached. This also means that the attorney does not get paid unless a recovery is made.</p><p>A personal injury lawyer fronts the litigation expenses, court costs and filing fees, and gets repaid out of the recovery amount.</p><p><span style="line-height: 1.6;">By working on a contingency fee basis, the lawyer has an incentive to work the case as efficiently and effectively as possible since he or she does not get paid unless the case is won.</span></p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/faqs/how-much-does-it-cost-to-get-a-personal-injury-attorney-.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-44674</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 10:30:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is the Statute of Limitations for a personal injury claim?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In Texas, you have two years to file a personal injury claim.</p><p>A statute of limitations is an amount of time you have to file a claim from the date of your accident. After the amount of time allowed by the statute has passed, you are not allowed to file a claim for that <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/practice_areas/get-justice-after-a-houston-car-accident.cfm">accident</a> except in certain circumstances. The statute of limitation begins to &ldquo;run&rdquo; from the date your accident occurred. That means the two year time period is calculated beginning with the day the accident happened. In some cases, when you can&rsquo;t notice your injury right away, the time to file a claim is calculated from the time begins when you could have or should have known about your injury.</p><p>If you are injured, don&rsquo;t wait two years to contact one of the <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/bio.cfm">experienced attorneys </a>at The Law Office of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/faqs/the-statute-of-limitations-for-a-personal-injury-claim-.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-44673</guid><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 11:05:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UNINSURED AND UNDERINSURED MOTORIST COVERAGE]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Automobile insurance exists to protect you from accidents that occur on the road or while you&rsquo;re in a covered motor vehicle. Occasionally, an automobile accident occurs and the driver who is at fault does not carry legally required insurance. If so, your insurance may be required to provide coverage for an accident.</p><p>Many insurance policies contain Uninsured motorist coverage and undersinsured motorist coverage. Uninsured motorist coverage (&ldquo;UM&rdquo;) and underinsured motorist coverage (&ldquo;UIM&rdquo;) help to reimburse you for costs incurred from injuries in an accident involving someone who does not carry the legally required automobile insurance.</p><p>If you are involved in an <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/practice_areas/get-justice-after-a-houston-car-accident.cfm">accident</a> when you are driving your own car, you are in a friend&rsquo;s car, or you are a pedestrian struck by a car and the driver at fault does not have legally required insurance coverage, you may be able to make a claim on your insurance policy to compensate you for the injuries you sustained.</p><p>UM/UIM coverage also applies if you are involved in a hit-and-run accident where there is no exchange of insurance information with the other driver. You may also make a claim on your insurance policy if you are injured in your friend&rsquo;s car, and your friend&rsquo;s insurance is not enough to cover your injuries.</p><p>If you have been involved in an accident with a driver who does not have sufficient insurance coverage to compensate you for your injuries or property damage, contact the Law Office of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C. for a free consultation with one of our experienced trial attorneys.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/uninsured-and-underinsured-motorist-coverage.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-137344</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 13:00:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is tire separation?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>That is when the tread comes off the rest of the tire.&nbsp; This can cause you to lose control of your vehicle and many times results in <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/practice_areas/get-justice-after-a-houston-car-accident.cfm">catastrophic injuries</a>.</p><p>One minute you are driving normally, and the next you don&rsquo;t have any tread on your tire.&nbsp; The tread is what keeps the tire connected to the road, it&rsquo;s what grips the road.&nbsp; If that is not there, you have little chance of controlling your vehicle.</p><p>If you have had a tire separation give us a call.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/faqs/what-is-tire-separation-.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-44581</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 11:49:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Know Your Legal Rights]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#39;ve been in a car accident, hit by an 18-wheeler, or hurt on the job. You need to know your legal rights.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/video/know-your-legal-rights.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-16919</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 12:05:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[JUSTICE FOR VICTIMS OF SEXUAL ASSAULT]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Sexual assault is a tragic, traumatic and devastating event for the victim and the victim&rsquo;s family members. While an individual who commits sexual assault against another may be subject to criminal prosecution and punishment, the road to recovery for victims and family members does not stop with a guilty verdict.</p><p>Victims of sexual assault sustain serious physical and mental injuries. Victims of sexual assault are often left with bills for medical treatment, which includes psychiatric treatment and therapy. In the case of a child who has been sexually abused, the bills for medical treatment and therapy are often high. Victims and family members are left to pay these medical bills which they would not have if not for the wrongdoing of another.</p><p>For an individual who has been injured in an accident in an automobile, at home, or at a business, there is typically automobile, homeowner&rsquo;s or commercial insurance to compensate those who have been injured as a result of the policy holder&rsquo;s negligent conduct.</p><p>Sexual assault, like any assault, is an intentional act. Intentional acts are not accidents, and therefore not covered by insurance policies. The rationale is that the insurer could not have contemplated an intentional act, like an assault, and should not be required by law to compensate for injuries which result from such conduct.</p><p>However,<a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/practice_areas/houston-premises-liability-attorney-fighting-for-you.cfm"> homeowner&rsquo;s insurance or commercial insurance</a> could still provide coverage for sexual assault. In some cases, the insured has a duty to reasonably supervise the abuser. When the insured breaches that duty, and an individual is sexually assaulted or abused, there is an actionable claim for negligent supervision. Likewise, if the sexual assault happens at the hands of an employee, the employer could be held liable for negligent hiring.</p><p>We will work hard to fight for the victims of sexual assault, and to help in any way in your road to recovery. Please call 713-228-3030 if you need representation.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/news/justice-for-victims-of-sexual-assault.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-50009</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 12:42:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Been in an Accident? Get Medical attention.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>First and foremost, if you are injured you need to get help.&nbsp; You cannot begin the road to recovery unless you consult with a medical professional about your symptoms.&nbsp; This should happen soon after the accident so the doctor can get to the root of the problem.</p><p>Another reason it is important to get medical help, and get it quickly, is to preserve the record.&nbsp; Getting medical attention soon after the accident will help to prove the accident was the cause of the symptoms you are experiencing.&nbsp; The longer you wait, it becomes more likely the insurance company of the other driver will try and say that the accident wasn&rsquo;t the cause of the pain you are experiencing, or the injuries to your body.</p><p>We recommend if you are in an accident that you get medical attention immediately.&nbsp; If you can&rsquo;t go right away, you need to go to the doctor within 2 weeks of the accident.&nbsp; Outside of 2 weeks, it becomes more difficult to show that the injuries complained of were caused by the accident that brought you here in the first place.&nbsp; Remember, a lot can happen in 2 weeks, and that is what the insurance company is going to argue.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/been-in-an-accident-get-medical-attention-.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-136709</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 17:45:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why would there be more than one firm working on my case?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>There are many reasons why having more than one firm working on your case is a good thing.</p><p>First, there are more resources available. &nbsp;Resources can be in the form on man-hours, attorneys available, or money for investigation.</p><p>Second, another set of eyes reviewing your case is helpful. &nbsp;To see the case from a different angle is a huge advantage. &nbsp;We all have different opinions.</p><p>Third, it helps spread the risk. &nbsp;This speaks more to the resources available. &nbsp;To investigate and gather records costs time and money. &nbsp;If 2 firms share in this cost, it frees up resources for other parts of your case.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/video/why-would-there-be-more-than-one-firm-working-on-my-case-.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-16902</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 12:28:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Los primeros pasos despues de un choque]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Los primeros pasos despues de un choque</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/video/los-pasos-primeros-despues-de-un-choque.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-16878</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 11:52:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to choose the Best Attorney]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Finding the right attorney for your case, whether you have been arrested, or you need to filed a lawsuit, is much like finding the right doctor.</p><p>1. &nbsp;The attorney should specialize in your type of case.</p><p>2. &nbsp;Bring all your documents for the attorney to review.</p><p>3. &nbsp;The attorney should be able to answer all your questions.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/video/how-to-choose-the-best-attorney.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-16877</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 11:15:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Your First Steps After a Car Accident]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>When you get into a car accident and it isn&#39;t your fault, it&#39;s a difficult process.</p><p>The first 3 things you need to do are.</p><p>1. Get a Police Report, or file the &quot;blue form&quot;.</p><p>2. Consult an Attorney before speaking with the other driver&#39;s insurance company.</p><p>3. Seek medical attentione. &nbsp;This is the most important step of all.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/video/car-accidents.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-16835</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 15:24:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Fight Back Smart in Your Texas Premises Liability Claim]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps you were going to see a movie with your friend when you slipped on a puddle in the bathroom and hit your head. Or perhaps you were shopping at your local convenience store when a large store display fell and broke your collarbone. No matter how it happens, being hurt because of someone else&rsquo;s carelessness is serious.</p><p>You may have thought that the property manager obviously could have prevented the hazard that caused you to get hurt if they had just taken a little extra care. Unfortunately, the insurance company representing the property manager may see it differently.</p><h2>What to Prove When Fighting Back in a Texas Premises Liability Claim</h2><p>Insurance adjusters that represent property managers are skilled at finding ways to pay you as little as possible in a settlement. The biggest trick they use to do this is to prove that you had at least some portion of fault in the accident.</p><p>To be smart about fighting your premises liability claim in Texas, you must prove:</p><ul><li>The property owner could foresee the potential for harm.</li><li>The property owner had control over the premises at the time of the accident.</li><li>The injuries you received were a direct result of your fall.</li><li>You did not have any portion of responsibility for your injuries.</li></ul><p>Although you may be confident that each of these statements is true, proving them to the insurance adjuster is another story. It requires significant research, experience, and an in-depth understanding of the law.</p><h3>Hiring a Texas Premises Liability Attorney Is a Smart Decision for Your Case</h3><p>Hiring someone to help you prove each of these points and fight on your behalf is a smart decision. Not only do you put someone who knows what to look for, how to document, and what to present in this type of claim, but you also give yourself the peace of mind you need to relax and recover.</p><p>We hate to see people get hurt. Worse yet, we hate to see innocent victims get taken advantage of by not being given the compensation they deserve.</p><p>Let our family of <a href="/practice_areas/houston-premises-liability-attorney-fighting-for-you.cfm">Texas premises liability attorneys</a> help your family pick up the pieces after a premises liability accident caused you pain. Call us today to get started on your claim and learn more about what we can do to help you in your specific case.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/how-to-fight-back-smart-in-your-texas-premises-liability-claim.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-129721</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:43:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[I fell while shopping, but I'm not sure if my fall is considered a slip and fall accident. What are some of the most common causes of slip and fall accidents in Houston?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><img alt="" src="https://dss.fosterwebmarketing.com/upload/galindolaw.com/Tripping.jpg" style="width: 251px; height: 175px; margin: 10px; float: right;" />The term &ldquo;slip and fall accident&rdquo; is a general term that describes a type of event that has the potential to cause serious injury. Sometimes these accidents are referred to as trip and fall accidents.</p><p>No matter what the term is, property owners are obligated to keep their premises safe from the risk of falling for their patrons. Some safety requirements include warnings of potentially dangerous areas, and keeping the facility properly maintained&mdash;including handrails, walkways, stairs, and more.</p><h2>Common Causes of Slip and Fall Accidents in Houston</h2><p>When you go shopping in Houston, it&rsquo;s understandable that you assume that hazards will be well marked and quickly taken care of to prevent the risk of harm to you, the patron. When that doesn&rsquo;t happen, you may have a case against the property owner whose carelessness hurt you.</p><p>Here are a few ways slip and fall accidents happen:</p><ul><li>Slip on water or spilled food in an unmarked puddle on the ground or floor</li><li>Trip over debris left in a walkway</li><li>Slip, or trip on uneven surfaces that are not properly marked</li><li>Dangerous construction or work sites that cause people to fall</li><li>Safety gear, such as handrails and guardrails, that are not properly maintained</li><li>Cracked or broken sidewalks, flooring, stairs, or escalators</li></ul><p>Often accidents of this nature cause serious injuries, such as broken hips, traumatic brain injuries, severe lacerations, tears, sprains, or strains. Unfortunately, accidents like these could and should have been prevented.</p><p>If you have fallen because of one of these situations or a similar instance, you may have a case against the owner or manager of the property. Knowing how to fight these cases can be difficult. We&rsquo;re happy to meet with you to discuss your case in greater detail to let you know what your options are. Schedule an appointment with our <a href="/practice_areas/houston-premises-liability-attorney-fighting-for-you.cfm">Houston slip and fall attorney</a> Cris Galindo to learn more about what you can do to protect your family against having to pay the price for high medical bills, lost wages, and more.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/faqs/top-causes-of-houston-slip-and-fall-accidents.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-39892</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:42:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Woman Files Premises Liability Claim in Texas Against HEB]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A Texas woman has filed a lawsuit against the grocery store chain, after a serious slip and fall accident left her severely injured.</p><p>Kathy Yassein filed the <a href="/practice_areas/houston-premises-liability-attorney-fighting-for-you.cfm">Texas premises liability lawsuit</a> on February 26 in Galveston County District Court against H.E. Butts Grocery Co. and HEB Grocery Co. LP.</p><p><img alt="" src="https://dss.fosterwebmarketing.com/upload/galindolaw.com/wet%20floor.jpg" style="width: 250px; height: 181px; margin: 10px; float: right;" />According to the official claim, Yassein was shopping in the HEB grocery store on Gulf Freeway in League City. As she walked into the store, she slipped on an accumulation of water in the store&rsquo;s front entrance. The fall was severe enough to cause her to fracture her femur.</p><p>The fracture was a serious enough injury, but the complications Yassein faced as a result of this broken bone made the situation much worse. The fall was so severe that she was required to have surgery to repair the damage to her bone. After surgery, Yassein contracted an infection. This infection prolonged her recovery, making it difficult for her to work, or perform her daily activities.</p><p>The popular Texas grocery chain has not publicly responded to the claim. It is accused of failing to provide safe premises for Yassein and their other shoppers.</p><p>In the lawsuit, Yassein is seeking over $100,000 in damages.</p><p>As premises liability attorneys in Texas, we&rsquo;ve seen many instances similar to Ms. Yassein&rsquo;s where store managers fail to properly maintain their stores. When puddles are not cleaned up in a timely manner and no signs are placed to alert shoppers to the hazard, people can easily slip and hurt themselves. As a result customers are not only injured, but they are also forced to retain a lawyer to fight back against big stores in order to receive compensation for their medical bills and lost wages.</p><p>We send our best wishes to Ms. Yassein as she battles the grocery store giant in her lawsuit.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/news/woman-files-premises-liability-claim-in-texas-against-heb.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-48187</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:40:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Five Critical Steps to Take When a Trip and Fall Accident in Houston Destroys Your Life]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><img alt="" src="https://dss.fosterwebmarketing.com/upload/galindolaw.com/Slipping.jpg" style="width: 250px; height: 223px; margin: 10px; float: left;" />You never expect it will happen to you. As you go about your day as usual, visiting your regular shops, meeting up with friends, or doing something fun with your family a crack in the sidewalk causes you to fall. You never saw the crack, but when your shoe meets the cracked cement, your body slams into the ground causing you to hit your head and break a bone.</p><p>Suddenly, your life is changed. You may be unable to work for months, costing you your paycheck. What&rsquo;s worse is that you may never fully recover from the damage caused to your body from these injuries.</p><h2>Five Ways to Protect Yourself After a Serious Trip and Fall Accident</h2><p>Knowing what to do immediately after a trip and fall accident may be equally as overwhelming. To help you stay protected and get the compensation you need, here are five tips from a Houston trip and fall lawyer.</p><ol><li><strong>Seek immediate medial care</strong>. When you suddenly lose your balance and fall to the ground, your adrenaline spikes. This can mask a lot of the pain and damage you experienced. Although you may think you&rsquo;ll be okay to wait a few days to see your doctor, it is critical that you seek <u>immediate</u> medical care. Getting fast care from a doctor could decrease the risk of making your injuries worse, and document the specific impact your fall had on your body. That will be important as you pursue your claim.</li><li><strong>Take photos. </strong>These days, most people carry a smartphone or camera. Use this to capture photos of what caused your injury as soon as the accident happened. Waiting until later to return to the scene to take pictures will mean losing the evidence of what the hazard looked like, and how poorly it was marked to warn you from falling. Take pictures right away to document what happened.</li><li><strong>Notify the property manager. </strong>You are badly hurt, and you do not want anyone else to experience the same pain and suffering as you have. That&rsquo;s why it is important to let the property manager know right away that there is a hazard that has the potential to cause someone serious harm. Talking to the property manager not only forces them to put up warning signs and fix the danger, but it also allows you to document your fall.</li><li><strong>Don&rsquo;t give a recorded statement. </strong>After you file a claim, the insurance adjuster representing the property owner may call and want to record your statement of what happened. This is dangerous, because it could put you at risk of losing at least a portion of the financial compensation you deserve. You have no obligation to give this statement, so it is best to politely decline.</li><li><strong>Don&rsquo;t sign any paperwork. </strong>A property owner may ask you to sign paperwork after the accident. They may disguise this as a document of what happened, but it may be used to put at least a portion of the blame against you later on in your claim. Avoid signing anything you&rsquo;re unfamiliar with. This is the best way to protect yourself from being scammed into taking blame for something that was not your fault.</li></ol><p>&nbsp;</p><p>When you trip and fall, your head is spinning. You shouldn&rsquo;t have to sift through paperwork, questioning, and more while you need to focus on recovering from your injuries. That&rsquo;s where attorney Cris Galindo can help.</p><p>Our team of <a href="/practice_areas/houston-premises-liability-attorney-fighting-for-you.cfm">Houston premise liability lawyers</a> knows how insurance companies handle trip and fall accidents. That means that we also know what they do to try to lower how much you receive in a settlement offer. With our help, you can protect your family and receive the full amount of compensation you deserve.</p><p>Still not sure about the steps you should take to protect yourself? Reach out to us and we&rsquo;ll get you started in the right direction.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/library/what-to-do-after-a-trip-and-fall-accident-in-houston.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-85632</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:29:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Help! I was badly hurt in an accident at work. What type of evidence do I need to document a work injury in Houston?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><img alt="" src="https://dss.fosterwebmarketing.com/upload/galindolaw.com/Work%20accident.jpg" style="width: 250px; height: 168px; margin: 10px; float: right;" />Getting injured on the job is very scary. You&rsquo;re smart to be thinking about what kind of records you need in order to document your work injury. With the right evidence, you can get the compensation you need to cover your medical expenses, lost wages, and more.</p><h2>Documents Needed When Filing a Houston Work Injury Claim</h2><p>Filing any type of injury claim requires a lot of work and a lot of evidence. You must prove a number of things in order for your employer to cover all of your costs, such as how the injury happened, and that the injury happened as a result of an accident at work. This is not always easy.</p><p>If your employer has workers&rsquo; compensation insurance, you must battle his insurance company to get the entire settlement value that you&rsquo;re entitled to. If your employer does not have workers&rsquo; compensation insurance, you may be put in a position where you have to battle your employer for the money needed to cover your medical bills and lost wages. Throughout all of this, you are watching your medical bills pile up and your checking account dwindle without a paycheck.</p><p>No matter how your case is handled, here are some of the most important types of documents for you to hold on to so that you get the compensation you deserve.</p><ul><li><strong>Medical bills. </strong>It&rsquo;s not cheap to have a serious injury treated, even if you have good health insurance. Keep track of all medical bills so that you can be reimbursed for your expenses.</li><li><strong>Time missed from work. </strong>You are entitled to receive a portion of your lost wages. Keep a journal of how many days you were forced to miss work because of your injury, and a doctor&rsquo;s note to support your claim.</li><li><strong>Take pictures. </strong>Pictures can paint a picture of what happened. Take pictures of as much as possible that had to do with your accident, such as the place where it happened, the injuries themselves, and anything else that may tell a story of what caused your injury.</li><li><strong>Witness statements. </strong>Did any of your coworkers see the accident? Document their statements of what happened for the record, while it&rsquo;s fresh in their mind.</li><li><strong>A journal. </strong>A serious injury will shake up your life. Keeping track of all of the critical details may be very difficult, if not impossible. By writing in a journal every day about your health, your symptoms, your activities (or lack thereof) and more, you will have a clear record of how your injury shook your life.</li></ul><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Did a <a href="/practice_areas/hurt-at-work-a-houston-work-injury-lawyer-can-help.cfm">work injury in Houston</a> (Link to Worksite Injuries PRACTICE AREA page) change your life? Let us know about what pieces of evidence you held on to that helped your claim in the comments below.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/faqs/how-to-document-your-houston-work-injury.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-39891</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:22:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Hire a Workplace Injury Lawyer in Houston?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The thought of getting hurt at work is terrifying. Not only could you suffer from the pain and anguish of an injury, but you could also suffer financially from lost wages and high medical costs. You may assume your boss will give you the money you need during this trying time, but unfortunately this is not always the case.</p><h2>A Houston Workplace Injury Lawyer May Be Able to Help</h2><p>You may not be the type of person who ever thought it would be necessary to hire a lawyer. However, as the bills pile up and your boss continues to refuse to help you out financially, you may quickly realize that a lawyer may be your best option for getting justice.</p><p>Here are the top reasons why people turn to lawyers to help them with their injury claim (and why you should too):</p><ul><li><strong>Understand your rights. </strong>When you&rsquo;re hurt at work, everything seems to move quickly. You are sent to the hospital quickly. The scene of the accident is cleaned up quickly. Within minutes you&rsquo;ve gone from earning a stable income to being hurt, and out of a paycheck. Your family deserves better&mdash;and you have rights. When you work with a Houston workplace lawyer, you can understand your rights and know what you can do to get justice.</li><li><strong>Discover which damages are available to you. </strong>There are a lot of costs associated with a workplace injury. You have your medical expenses, your lost wages, your pain and suffering punitive damages, and more. Keeping all of these damages straight is difficult, especially if you&rsquo;re not well-versed in workers&rsquo; compensation laws in Texas. A lawyer can help you understand your rights and what types of damages you may be able to recover.</li><li><strong>Get help fighting back so you can focus on your recovery. </strong>The most important thing for you to focus on right now is your recovery, but with all the mounting bills and lack of a paycheck, recovery may be the last thing on your mind. With help from a lawyer, you can give your body the rest and relaxation it needs to make a full and fast recovery.</li></ul><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Putting a lawyer on your side can help you have confidence in how your claim is handled. By working with someone familiar with workplace injury law, you will know that you are getting the best possible outcome in a devastating situation. If you&rsquo;re not sure, we encourage you to reach out to us with questions abut your specific case. We&rsquo;ll let you know if hiring a <a href="/practice_areas/hurt-at-work-a-houston-work-injury-lawyer-can-help.cfm">workplace injury lawyer in Houston</a> is right for you.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/why-hire-a-workplace-injury-lawyer-in-houston-.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-129720</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:19:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Family Sues After a Fatal Harris County Industrial Accident]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>A construction worker was killed while working at the new football stadium on Baylor University&rsquo;s campus. Now, the family has filed a wrongful death lawsuit against the university and the construction and equipment companies after this shocking Harris County industrial accident.</p><p><img alt="" src="https://dss.fosterwebmarketing.com/upload/galindolaw.com/fatal%20accident.jpg" style="width: 250px; height: 167px; margin: 10px; float: right;" />Jose Dario Suarez, 55, drowned when a hydraulic lift he and one other worker were strapped to slipped and rolled down a barge into the Brazos River. The accident happened as both men were working on a pedestrian bridge over the river behind Baylor Law School. Unlike his coworker, Suarez was unable to untie himself from the barge after it went into the river. Divers located his body four hours after the accident.</p><p>Suarez&rsquo;s wife, two daughters, son, and mother are all seeking damages after the catastrophic accident.</p><p>The companies being sued in their lawsuit include Flexifloat Construction Systems in Houston, Baylor University, Austin Commercial Inc., Austin Bridge and Road, Derr and Isbell Construction Inc., and Genie Industries Inc.</p><p>Austin Commercial, Austin Bridge and Road, and Derr and Isbell were the construction companies in charge of the walking bridge over the Brazos River between the campus and the new stadium.</p><p>The Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) is also investigating the fatal Harris County accident. The report has not been released.</p><p>Among the items they&rsquo;re investigating is why the equipment sunk to the bottom of the river, drowning Suarez. Flexifloat is the company responsible for manufacturing the barge Suarez and his coworker were on at the time of the accident.</p><p>According to the lawyers representing the Suarez family, the only way they would get access to the evidence was to file a lawsuit. The lawsuit alleges that faulty design of the barge may have been to blame for the accident.</p><p>We send our heartfelt condolences to the entire Suarez family for their loss.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/news/family-sues-after-a-fatal-harris-county-industrial-accident.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-48185</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:11:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Five Things You Should Do After a Construction Accident in Houston]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><img alt="" src="https://dss.fosterwebmarketing.com/upload/galindolaw.com/Construction%20accident.jpg" style="width: 250px; height: 167px; margin: 10px; float: right;" />Work on any construction site in Houston and you&rsquo;ll know that there are hundreds of hazards scattered around. Your employer works hard to keep you safe from those hazards (or at least he should) by setting out a number of rules and guidelines. If someone makes an error or breaks from the rules put in place, you could get seriously hurt.</p><h2>What to Do After an Injury on a Houston Construction Site</h2><p>If you were hurt on a worksite, the steps you take following your injury can have a major impact on your claim. Here are five things you must do to protect your family:</p><ul><li><strong>Let your supervisor know about the accident. </strong>The first thing you must do following an accident on a construction worksite is let your supervisor know. You don&rsquo;t want anyone else to get hurt in the same unsafe area. Letting them know about the risk allows them to secure it as quickly as possible. It also documents exactly what happened.</li><li><strong>Get medical care. </strong>Going to the doctor or emergency room may seem like the last thing you want to do. However, not getting medical care right away can cost you physically and financially down the road. No matter how minor your injury may seem, it is important that you seek medical attention as soon as possible after a serious accident.</li><li><strong>Keep a journal with all your records. </strong>The paperwork and records for your injury play an important role when trying to get a fair settlement. Keep notes of your symptoms, your visits to the doctor, and about any talks you may have with others. With this information written down, you won&rsquo;t have to worry about not remembering an important detail.</li><li><strong>Take pictures. </strong>Another important piece of evidence is images documenting what happened. Take pictures of the worksite where the injury happened, the damage to your body, and any other images that could help you tell the story visually of what happened to you.</li><li><strong>Contact a construction site injury lawyer. </strong>Filing a claim against your employer, subcontractor or a general contractor is not easy. You have enough to focus on while you recover from your injuries without having to worry about whether or not you&rsquo;re getting full justice and compensation. With help from a <a href="/practice_areas/hurt-at-work-a-houston-work-injury-lawyer-can-help.cfm">Houston worksite injury lawyer</a> skilled in fighting these claims, you can rest easy with the peace of mind that your claim is being handled in the best way possible.</li></ul><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Serious injuries can happen as a result of someone not paying attention or following the rules when working in a hazardous area. If you know of someone who was hurt in a construction site, we encourage you to share this article with him so that he can be sure to follow all the necessary steps and get a fair settlement for his claim.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/library/how-to-handle-your-houston-construction-accident.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-85631</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:03:00 EST</pubDate></item>
</channel>
</rss>