<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
    <atom:link href="http://www.galindolaw.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
     <title>Law offices of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C. Blog</title>
     <link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/</link>
     <description>Law offices of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C. Blog</description>
     <language>en-us</language>
     <copyright>2015 Law offices of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C., All Rights Reserved, Reproduced with Permission</copyright>
     <docs>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/</docs>
     <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 11:08:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
     <image>
        <title>Law offices of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C. Blog</title>
        <url>http://www.galindolaw.com/images/logoprint.gif</url>
        <link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/</link>
     </image>
    
<item><title><![CDATA[Injury Caused by Teen or Unlicensed Drivers]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Under Texas law, if you give permission to a driver who you know is unlicensed, incompetent or reckless to operate your vehicle; you may be held liable for their negligent acts. This is known as negligent entrustment.</p><p>Likewise, if you are injured by an unlicensed, incompetent or reckless driver, it does not mean that you or your insurance company will be stuck paying your medical bills and costs to repair your vehicle. You may seek compensation for your injuries from the owner of the other vehicle as well as the driver who caused the accident.</p><p>In a negligent entrustment suit, the driver who causes the <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/practice_areas/get-justice-after-a-houston-car-accident.cfm">accident</a> is sometimes excluded or not covered by the automobile insurance policy which the owner of the vehicle carries. This happens frequently when an unlicensed teenager is entrusted with the use of their parent&rsquo;s vehicle and causes an accident. An owner of a car may also be liable if the owner lent his or her car to someone they knew had a history of car accidents.</p><p>&nbsp;If you are involved in an accident in which the other driver is someone other than the owner, there are sources of monetary compensation available under Texas law.</p><p>Contact the law office of Cristobal Galindo, P.C. for <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/bio.cfm">experienced lawyers</a> to represent you if you are injured in such an accident.&nbsp;</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/injury-caused-by-teen-or-unlicensed-drivers.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-137346</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 12:34:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[UNINSURED AND UNDERINSURED MOTORIST COVERAGE]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Automobile insurance exists to protect you from accidents that occur on the road or while you&rsquo;re in a covered motor vehicle. Occasionally, an automobile accident occurs and the driver who is at fault does not carry legally required insurance. If so, your insurance may be required to provide coverage for an accident.</p><p>Many insurance policies contain Uninsured motorist coverage and undersinsured motorist coverage. Uninsured motorist coverage (&ldquo;UM&rdquo;) and underinsured motorist coverage (&ldquo;UIM&rdquo;) help to reimburse you for costs incurred from injuries in an accident involving someone who does not carry the legally required automobile insurance.</p><p>If you are involved in an <a href="http://www.galindolaw.com/practice_areas/get-justice-after-a-houston-car-accident.cfm">accident</a> when you are driving your own car, you are in a friend&rsquo;s car, or you are a pedestrian struck by a car and the driver at fault does not have legally required insurance coverage, you may be able to make a claim on your insurance policy to compensate you for the injuries you sustained.</p><p>UM/UIM coverage also applies if you are involved in a hit-and-run accident where there is no exchange of insurance information with the other driver. You may also make a claim on your insurance policy if you are injured in your friend&rsquo;s car, and your friend&rsquo;s insurance is not enough to cover your injuries.</p><p>If you have been involved in an accident with a driver who does not have sufficient insurance coverage to compensate you for your injuries or property damage, contact the Law Office of Cristobal M. Galindo, P.C. for a free consultation with one of our experienced trial attorneys.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/uninsured-and-underinsured-motorist-coverage.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-137344</guid><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 13:00:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Been in an Accident? Get Medical attention.]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>First and foremost, if you are injured you need to get help.&nbsp; You cannot begin the road to recovery unless you consult with a medical professional about your symptoms.&nbsp; This should happen soon after the accident so the doctor can get to the root of the problem.</p><p>Another reason it is important to get medical help, and get it quickly, is to preserve the record.&nbsp; Getting medical attention soon after the accident will help to prove the accident was the cause of the symptoms you are experiencing.&nbsp; The longer you wait, it becomes more likely the insurance company of the other driver will try and say that the accident wasn&rsquo;t the cause of the pain you are experiencing, or the injuries to your body.</p><p>We recommend if you are in an accident that you get medical attention immediately.&nbsp; If you can&rsquo;t go right away, you need to go to the doctor within 2 weeks of the accident.&nbsp; Outside of 2 weeks, it becomes more difficult to show that the injuries complained of were caused by the accident that brought you here in the first place.&nbsp; Remember, a lot can happen in 2 weeks, and that is what the insurance company is going to argue.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/been-in-an-accident-get-medical-attention-.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-136709</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 17:45:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Fight Back Smart in Your Texas Premises Liability Claim]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps you were going to see a movie with your friend when you slipped on a puddle in the bathroom and hit your head. Or perhaps you were shopping at your local convenience store when a large store display fell and broke your collarbone. No matter how it happens, being hurt because of someone else&rsquo;s carelessness is serious.</p><p>You may have thought that the property manager obviously could have prevented the hazard that caused you to get hurt if they had just taken a little extra care. Unfortunately, the insurance company representing the property manager may see it differently.</p><h2>What to Prove When Fighting Back in a Texas Premises Liability Claim</h2><p>Insurance adjusters that represent property managers are skilled at finding ways to pay you as little as possible in a settlement. The biggest trick they use to do this is to prove that you had at least some portion of fault in the accident.</p><p>To be smart about fighting your premises liability claim in Texas, you must prove:</p><ul><li>The property owner could foresee the potential for harm.</li><li>The property owner had control over the premises at the time of the accident.</li><li>The injuries you received were a direct result of your fall.</li><li>You did not have any portion of responsibility for your injuries.</li></ul><p>Although you may be confident that each of these statements is true, proving them to the insurance adjuster is another story. It requires significant research, experience, and an in-depth understanding of the law.</p><h3>Hiring a Texas Premises Liability Attorney Is a Smart Decision for Your Case</h3><p>Hiring someone to help you prove each of these points and fight on your behalf is a smart decision. Not only do you put someone who knows what to look for, how to document, and what to present in this type of claim, but you also give yourself the peace of mind you need to relax and recover.</p><p>We hate to see people get hurt. Worse yet, we hate to see innocent victims get taken advantage of by not being given the compensation they deserve.</p><p>Let our family of <a href="/practice_areas/houston-premises-liability-attorney-fighting-for-you.cfm">Texas premises liability attorneys</a> help your family pick up the pieces after a premises liability accident caused you pain. Call us today to get started on your claim and learn more about what we can do to help you in your specific case.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/how-to-fight-back-smart-in-your-texas-premises-liability-claim.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-129721</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:43:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Hire a Workplace Injury Lawyer in Houston?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The thought of getting hurt at work is terrifying. Not only could you suffer from the pain and anguish of an injury, but you could also suffer financially from lost wages and high medical costs. You may assume your boss will give you the money you need during this trying time, but unfortunately this is not always the case.</p><h2>A Houston Workplace Injury Lawyer May Be Able to Help</h2><p>You may not be the type of person who ever thought it would be necessary to hire a lawyer. However, as the bills pile up and your boss continues to refuse to help you out financially, you may quickly realize that a lawyer may be your best option for getting justice.</p><p>Here are the top reasons why people turn to lawyers to help them with their injury claim (and why you should too):</p><ul><li><strong>Understand your rights. </strong>When you&rsquo;re hurt at work, everything seems to move quickly. You are sent to the hospital quickly. The scene of the accident is cleaned up quickly. Within minutes you&rsquo;ve gone from earning a stable income to being hurt, and out of a paycheck. Your family deserves better&mdash;and you have rights. When you work with a Houston workplace lawyer, you can understand your rights and know what you can do to get justice.</li><li><strong>Discover which damages are available to you. </strong>There are a lot of costs associated with a workplace injury. You have your medical expenses, your lost wages, your pain and suffering punitive damages, and more. Keeping all of these damages straight is difficult, especially if you&rsquo;re not well-versed in workers&rsquo; compensation laws in Texas. A lawyer can help you understand your rights and what types of damages you may be able to recover.</li><li><strong>Get help fighting back so you can focus on your recovery. </strong>The most important thing for you to focus on right now is your recovery, but with all the mounting bills and lack of a paycheck, recovery may be the last thing on your mind. With help from a lawyer, you can give your body the rest and relaxation it needs to make a full and fast recovery.</li></ul><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Putting a lawyer on your side can help you have confidence in how your claim is handled. By working with someone familiar with workplace injury law, you will know that you are getting the best possible outcome in a devastating situation. If you&rsquo;re not sure, we encourage you to reach out to us with questions abut your specific case. We&rsquo;ll let you know if hiring a <a href="/practice_areas/hurt-at-work-a-houston-work-injury-lawyer-can-help.cfm">workplace injury lawyer in Houston</a> is right for you.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/why-hire-a-workplace-injury-lawyer-in-houston-.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-129720</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 19:19:00 EST</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Protect Your Rights After a Beaumont Car Crash]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>When another driver slams into your car, you&rsquo;re suddenly faced with a million thoughts. What happened? What should you do? What are your rights? Who is going to pay for all your time missed from work and medical costs?</p><p>Car accidents have serious, long-lasting consequences. You may have significant&mdash;possibly permanent&mdash;damage to your back, neck, or brain after a crash. You may suffer from shattered bones due to the impact. Any catastrophic injury needs to be cared for immediately, and the person who caused the injury must be held responsible.</p><h2>Your Rights As a Beaumont Car Accident Victim</h2><p>Although it may seem obvious that the driver who caused the crash should be held accountable for your injuries, many times that just doesn&rsquo;t happen. Innocent drivers are often forced to pay for the mistakes of someone else. To prevent this from happening to you, you need to know your rights.</p><p>Here are a few things you can do to protect yourself and your rights after a serious crash:</p><ul><li>Immediately call the police. Having a police report document what happened at the scene of the crash is a strong piece of evidence for what happened in the crash.</li><li>Avoid unnecessary communication&mdash;such as conversation about what happened in the crash&mdash;with the other driver or any witnesses. This could harm you later.</li><li>Get all contact information from the witnesses and the other driver.</li><li>Call and let your own insurance company know you were in a car crash.</li><li>Gather evidence from the crash, such as taking pictures of the vehicles, other property damage, the crash site, and your injuries.</li><li>Keep a detailed journal of all of your symptoms, injuries, medical treatments, and costs.</li><li>Follow all doctor recommendations and attend all follow-up appointments.</li></ul><p>Following these guidelines immediately after the crash will help you later in your settlement when it comes time to prove who was at fault for the crash. Unfortunately, even when you follow these guidelines and do everything you&rsquo;re supposed to do, the insurance adjuster will still try to find ways to prove you had some portion of fault in the collision.</p><h2>A Car Accident Lawyer Can Defend Your Rights</h2><p>Having a <a href="/practice_areas/get-justice-after-a-houston-car-accident.cfm">Beaumont car accident lawyer</a> on your side can help! When you allow our family to represent your family through the settlement process, you can ensure that your rights are not violated and that you get the justice you deserve. Call us today to find out how we can help you get what you deserve in your settlement claim.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.galindolaw.com/blog/how-to-protect-your-rights-after-a-beaumont-car-crash.cfm</link><guid isPermaLink="false">www.galindolaw.com-129479</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 21:02:00 EST</pubDate></item>
</channel>
</rss>